Come along now, Alphonse.
That must have hurt,
but it's okay now.
I'll make it better right away.
Remember? Like I did
when you were a little boy.
Mom?
Yes.
Mama...
The Philosopher's Stone.
Those who obtain it are set free from the Law of Equivalent Exchange.
There is no need to pay a price
in order to obtain something, either.
We sought it and found it.
Let...
Let me try again, please!
Al-kun, please,
I beg you.
Your role in this is over, Tucker.
Brother...
You homunculus, get away from Al!
Brother, this is...
Yeah, I was taken in as well.
But that isn't Mom.
I'm aware of that too, but...
No matter whose form
she may resemble,
that thing doesn't have a soul!
What an awful thing to say, Edward.
Please, Al-kun...
Tucker! You intentionally
called Al here by himself?!
It's equivalent exchange. By using the Philosopher's Stone, this is what happened.
You were suckered
into this by Tucker!
Dammit, there's getting to be too many people I'm planning to whale on later,
and if I don't make notes or something of them all, I'm going to forget!
Never mind. Right now, you're coming with me.
He can't do that, Ed.
Are you going to
return Al back to normal?
Or are you just going to let the whole rest of Al's body
be used up by this
"you-know-who" person?!
Al, get out of the way!
Brother!
You stay out of the way!
That hurt, Edward.
I know it's going to take
more than that for you to die.
Don't run away.
What's this?
It's the transmutation circle
that was drawn inside Dante-san's house when I defeated Greed.
This is what seals up
you homunculi, right?
You're smart, aren't you?
But this alone is not enough.
I know. It also takes a
homunculus' only weakness—
a portion of the
body of the person
who was the object of the attempt at resurrection by human transmutation.
Brother, what is that?!
The object of the human transmutation that gave rise to this homunculus.
Mom...
Brother, you dug up Mom's grave
without telling me!
I'm the only one who
needed to go through that!
It's no use, Sloth.
Doing that won't erase
the transmutation circle.
I carved it deep with
these nails, after all.
Thanks.
It's not like I did it
because I wanted that thing.
Why... would you betray the One?
Sloth,
do you really not
remember anything?
What are you talking about?
I remember.
It's just a little bit, but still...
There's no reason why
we should have any memories.
Maybe it's just that the thoughts of the person
who performs human transmutation are so strong,
and the memories of
the deceased get burned in.
Still, even so,
I do have memories.
I was...
an Ishbalan woman.
Stop it.
If the memories of before you were born
were ever to return to you...
Stop it, Lust!
...then it will be you
that gets a glimpse of hell.
Al! What are you doing?!
Brother, you can't use
Mom's body to do this!
Al, if we don't kill them,
they're going to be after you forever!
But if you were able to stop her with that, then that's what that means, right?
She's what was born back then.
Al, she's a homunculus!
A homunculus is born during
a failed human transmutation.
Even if she doesn't have a soul...
Please, Al!
We're the ones who made her!
That's right! That's why we have to bury her!
We can't!
Al!
In that case, I'll do it.
Go pick it up, Fullmetal boy. We can still seal her.
You were trying to
pick on Mama using this, huh?
Mama?
Wrath, she is not your mother!
I've decided to take everything of yours away from you.
She's not my mother either.
Then I'll take her.
Hand it over.
What are you doing to Mama?!
Mama?
He's looking for a mother,
and he's found a substitute.
Stop, I tell you!
Come on, let's go.
Al!
I will handle Wrath.
You're a little old to be longing for mother's milk, aren't you?
That won't do any good. I can keep coming back to life forever.
As many times as you have red stones, right?
Which is why...
I will kill you as many times...
as it takes...
to use them up.
I'm...
going to become him!
What would doing that make you?
Well, for that matter...
what am I doing here at all?!
The whole thing was
a mistake from the start.
Have you forgotten?
I can use alchemy!
Al!
I'm sorry!
I can't get free!
If I touch him, there'll be a reaction,
and there's no telling what will happen!
Yes, so it seems. So back off.
Mom!
You get it now, Al? She's not Mom!
Mom wouldn't say something like that!
She wouldn't use you as a shield, Al!
And she wouldn't hit me!
Brother!
You can't touch your brother, so you're trying to use a transmutation circle.
But I won't give you
enough time to draw one!
Brother!
That was enough!
Al!
Isn't this what you wanted?
You wanted to become human so you could die, didn't you?
I wanted to die...
Is that it?
I...
wanted to die?
If I become human...
does it just mean death?
Then, what is it to be
completely human?
Can't you answer me?!
You're a human!
Mama...
That's right...
I have to protect Mama.
Al, sorry about that.
Mm-mm, I'm the one who's sorry.
Come to think of it,
where's Lust?
That night...
That night, I...
I saw you...
Edward.
Eat these.
They are his sons, after all.
I knew this would happen.
She's starting to look a little more presentable, huh?
You all used to
look like that as well.
What...
was that?
There were children...
two of them...
and a husband.
I was happy...
and yet very...
sad.
You will understand
once you become human.
Human?
I will assist you.
Find the Philosopher's Stone.
How about I place her at your side?
There is a vacant military registry
that I used during the Ishbal incident.
She can slip in using that.
Yes. If you were to
take her home with you,
your adorable wife would become jealous, huh?
Sloth...
As of today,
you are Sloth.
Is she vibrating her cells and generating heat?
Edward...
Stop pretending to be Mom!
You don't even have any of her memories!
I do have memories.
Like Lust said,
maybe the thoughts of your mother
within you were just burned into me.
You're lying! If that were so,
you wouldn't be able to do this!
It's why...
I'm able to do this.
I do have memories.
Memories of myself as your mother...
And yet,
your mother is dead.
I am...
not human.
Who am I?
I am...
going to kill you.
By doing so, I can prove
that I am not your mother.
If you were no longer here,
I wouldn't be tormented by these memories.
I am not your mother, and yet...
I feel I am your mother.
I almost feel as though
I could love you.
You created me.
I'm supposed to hate you.
Brother, what should we do?!
This is the form
our sin has taken on!
Mama!
I am not your mother.
I have no intention
of holding you.
Brother...
Mama!
I transmuted my Automail into sodium.
It explodes when it
reacts with water.
Mama! Mama!
Stop it!
She wasn't anyone's mama.
Your mama is dead.
Mama! Mama!
Mama!
No matter what you do,
I am not going to die.
Mama!
Stay back, Wrath.
Mama, I'm going to
become one with you!
He fused himself with another homunculus?
Wrath...
What have you done?
He took the portion of my mom
I brought with me inside his own body.
With it that close to you,
you can't move, can you?
I'm going to reconstruct
all of the material
you're composed of
into another material.
That's not possible, Brother!
You can't transmute a person's body!
I realized something
during my fight with Greed.
I rearranged the elements he was composed of.
It's not like what Kimbly did,
when he restructured the
elements in just one place.
I'll be able to restructure
the entire body.
The reason being
that a homunculus...
is not human!
Mama...
What did you do?!
What did you do to Mama?!
Get away from her.
Get away from her now.
Mama?
I restructured your water into ethanol.
It vaporizes at room temperature.
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 48: "Good-bye"
Mom... Colonel... Al...
This is the path I have chosen.